<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="#style"?>
<document>
	<concept>
		<title>Wisdom</title>
		<section>
			<bold>Right Data</bold>
			<p>
				is the basis for Geekdom.  In order to understand, you must have a 
				basis for knowledge, and knowledge comes from both experience and 
				study.  Your data should have integrity, and you must use constant
				MD5 checksums to be sure that it is properly copied.  You must patch 
				files so that they improve, and you must organize it for easy retrieval.
			</p>
		</section>
		<section>
			<bold>Right Motivation</bold>
			<p>
				guides the practice of Right Data.  Your decisions over morality and 
				technological progress should be firmly rooted in Right Data, and 
				having a proper motivation is essential to accomplishing this.  
				Right Motivation should always be guided by the principles of 
				user-friendliness, but can be confined to a targeted base of users 
				to better enhance usability and productivity.  The ability to see 
				your user-base and take decisions with Right Data as context should 
				harmonize with end-users and developers alike.
			</p>
		</section>
	</concept>
	<concept>
		<title>Ethical Conduct</title>
		<section>
			<bold>Right Partitioning</bold>
			<p>
				allows you to separate and manage data.  Unix permissions are not 
				preserved in FAT32, and the NTFS 'hidden' flag isn't respected in 
				HFS+.  Ext3 is backwards compatible as ext2, but journaling is lost.  
				Each partition serves a purpose, and each file system has its strengths 
				and weaknesses.  As such, you should take care when copying files back 
				and forth to not alter its integrity.  Each system has its ins and outs, 
				and only through co-operation can data be properly passed from one to 
				another without loss of quality or attributes.  
			</p>
			<p>
				Partitioning helps this, but only when it contributes to the overall 
				functioning of the system, and not when it is just for partitioning's 
				sake.  Sometimes, partitions should be merged, or used simultaneously 
				for one system, and so on.  Partitioning should be used for the overall 
				unity of the system.  This is not limited to hard drives; gadgets, 
				ideas, and people should harmonize through optimal organization for the 
				overall unity of geek-kind.
			</p>
		</section>
		<section>
			<bold>Right Backup</bold>
			<p>
				allows for preservation.  Incremental backups are extremely helpful, 
				but full system backups are essential.  No loss of data should occur 
				if it can be helped, and timely recovery is of crucial importance.  
				Do not take unnecessary risks with irrecoverable data.  All users' 
				data is equally valuable, so do not let anyone be without backup.  
				This applies to all data, digital and otherwise.
			</p>
		</section>
		<section>
			<bold>Right Security</bold>
			<p>
				goes hand in hand with backup.  Data stewardship is as much every 
				admin's responsibility as it is every user's.  Each should do their 
				part towards building a secure environment for all, and helpfully 
				encourage others to do the same.  In this way, you can more 
				efficiently contribute towards the end-user's (as well as developer's) 
				experience.  Applying this in a real-life way means to assess risk-taking 
				behaviors and work for the well-being of geeks everywhere.  Right 
				Security is integral to laying the path for digital harmony.
			</p>
		</section>
	</concept>
	<concept>
		<title>Concentration</title>
		<section>
			<bold>Right Administrator</bold>
			<p>
				is the application of the Eightfold Noble Geek Path to not just the 
				systems that bring people together, but to the users themselves.  
				Principles of systems do not always apply to people, at least not 
				in a ready form, and neither do principles of dealing with people 
				apply directly to systems.  Being able to differentiate between 
				the two and respond accordingly is important.  Interpretation of 
				rules and ethics can vary from person to person, and there is no 
				universal transition layer.  Because of this, it takes focus and 
				study, and an entirely separate set of skills to be able to both 
				administrate and moderate users.  The social nature of moderation 
				helps all to learn how to use the publicly available 'human APIs.'
			</p>
		</section>
		<section>
			<bold>Right Observation</bold>
			<p>
				is a state of awareness that is developed through study and 
				dedication.  It is the ability to apply a passive attention so 
				as to learn to observe as objectively as possible, and subjectively 
				as needed.  It is the sys-admin's ability to monitor server status, 
				the moderator's ability to view forum posts, the end user's ability 
				to view content, and the developer's ability to parse code.  Right 
				Observation grants one the ability to witness struggle but to not 
				be swayed by it.  It allows the individual's awareness to gain 
				access to more uncorrupted streams of data, and to parse through 
				tampered bits with relative ease.  It forms the basis for Right 
				Developing.
			</p>
		</section>
		<section>
			<bold>Right Developing</bold>
			<p>
				is the dedication of contribution to, and experience of, code.  
				Those who give their life to the sometimes monastic practice of 
				programming can, just as through meditation, gain spiritual discipline.  
				This allows them to be at peace with any script, program, system, and 
				network, to transcend 0s and 1s via an experience of non-duality and 
				oneness.  Continual Developing hones this state of being further until 
				there is no distinction between coder and code.
			</p>
		</section>
	</concept>
	<concept>
		<title>Summary</title>
		<section>
			<bold>There is suffering</bold>
			<p>
				our technological world, and it has a cause: attachment.  
				Attachment to the newest gadget of the day, the bleeding-edge release of some 
				particular software, even the virus-riddled attachments of email.  Take refuge 
				in the greatest network alive, and maybe you can gain some peace from the 
				Eightfold Noble Geek Path.
			</p>
		</section>
	</concept>
	<footer id="style">
		concept	{display: block}
		title	{display: block; font-size: 18pt; text-decoration: underline}
		section {display: block; margin: 15px 20px 15px 20px}
		bold	{font-weight: bold; font-size: 13pt; font-variant: small-caps}
        footer  {display: none}
	</footer>
</document>